ukfederation.org.uk 2009-11-26

# UK Federation Information Centre | Documents / PrivacyPolicy browse

## JANET(UK) PRIVACY POLICY

### General

We want to protect the privacy of visitors to our website and of individuals who give us their personal details. Please read the following policy; it will help you to understand how we use personal data. We may change our privacy policy at any time without giving you notice, so please check it each time you visit this website. 

**Whenever you give us personal data, you are consenting to its collection and use in accordance with this privacy policy.**

### What personal data do we collect?

We log your Internet Protocol (IP) address in order to receive and send information from and to you over the internet.   
When you register for any of our conferences, workshops, courses or other services, make an enquiry, report a problem, register a domain name, join one of our mailing lists or order products or services from us, you may be asked to provide some personal data such as your name, home, business or billing address, telephone number, e-mail address, and credit or debit card number.   
Bear in mind that if you submit any personal data for inclusion in any directory or information service, it may be seen by anyone visiting this website, or who has access to that directory or information service. Do not submit any personal data that you do not want to be made public in this way, and please do not send us any personal data about anyone else without their permission. In particular, when you apply for a membership account or to register or amend a domain name registration, you must obtain the consent of anyone whose personal data you provide to us. 

### Cookies

We may use cookies.   
A cookie is a small piece of data or message that is sent from a web server to your browser and may be stored on your hard drive. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Cookies do not damage your system.   
You can reset your browser so as to refuse any cookie or to alert you to when a cookie is being sent. If you refuse cookies, some websites may not function. 

### How do we use your personal data?

We use your personal data to provide goods and services to you or your organisation, to carry out domain name registration and administration, to let you know about other goods and services in which you may be interested, to inform you about changes and improvements to our website, and for direct marketing purposes (but we do give you the option to opt out of this).   
We may also use your personal data to monitor the use of our website, to record traffic flows and to carry out research about our visitors’ and customers’ demographics, interests and behaviour. We do this to understand our visitors, customers and potential customers better.   
When you give us personal data, those data may be sent electronically to servers anywhere in the world and may be used, stored and processed anywhere in the world, including countries outside the European Economic Area. (Bear in mind that many countries outside the EEA do not adequately protect your rights as a data subject.)   
Whenever and wherever we collect, process or use personal data, we take steps to ensure that it is treated securely and in accordance with our privacy policy. 

### To whom might we disclose your personal data?

We may pass your personal data to anyone who needs those data in order to fulfil your requests for our goods and services, or to validate any payment details you give to us. Some of these people may be located outside the European Economic Area (EEA).   
Please note that personal data provided to us in connection with domain name registration will be made available to the public via our WHOIS server, and we may make that information available to anyone who appears to us to make a bona fide request for information about the registrant of any domain name.   
We may pass your personal data to our data processors. Some of these may be located outside the European Economic Area.   
We may also provide your personal data to businesses which may be located outside the European Economic Area and who may use the data to send you information about other products or services. However, you may opt-out of your personal data being used in this way when we collect your personal data.   
We may also provide your personal data to anyone to whom our business or business assets are transferred.   
Except as set out above, we will not disclose your personal data unless we are obliged to do so or allowed to do so by law, or where we need to do so in order to run our business (for instance where we outsource services or other people process data for us). 

### Direct Marketing

Unless you have already informed us that you do not wish us to do so, we may contact you by e-mail to market our goods and services. You may at any time request us to stop using your personal data for direct marketing purposes. If you wish to do this please contact: [service@janet.ac.uk](mailto:service@janet.ac.uk)

### Links

Our website contains links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. We encourage our visitors to be aware when they leave our website, and to read the privacy policy of other sites that collect or use personal data. This privacy policy applies only to personal data collected by JANET(UK). 

### Security

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the internet or any other network can be guaranteed as 100% secure, but we take appropriate steps to try to protect the security of your personal data. 

### Contacts

This is the website of the JNT Association trading as JANET(UK), a not-for-profit company limited by guarantee. Our registered number is 2881024 and our registered office is at Lumen House, Library Avenue, Harwell Science and Innovation Campus, Didcot, Oxfordshire, OX11 0SG.   
Individuals have certain rights of access to their personal data. If you want to request any information about your personal data, please contact: [service@janet.ac.uk](mailto:service@janet.ac.uk)

### Inaccuracies and Corrections

We would like to keep your personal data accurate and up to date. If you become aware of any errors or inaccuracies please let us know by contacting: [service@janet.ac.uk](mailto:service@janet.ac.uk)
